# **Nolan Kurylo**

**≅**(403) 809-2980 **in**nolan-kurylo **⊙**nolankurylo **§**nolankurylo.github.io ⊠nolankurylo@gmail.com

Software Engineer specialized in Machine Learning with 3+ years of experience in Python and C++. 3+ years deploying scalable applications and ML models on AWS under microservices architecture. 3+ years leading software developers in Agile and Scrum based environments.

#### **Education**

## **Bachelor of Software Engineering (Co-op - BSEng)**

**University of Victoria** 

GPA - 3.9/4.0 (8.3/9.0)

Sept. 2017 – Aug. 2022

Specialization in Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, and Data Mining and Analysis

#### Skills

- **Programming Languages -** Python, C, C++, Java, Javascript
- Big Data Apache PySpark, Databricks, Hadoop
- ML Tools TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, HuggingFace, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib
- Cloud Computing AWS (Cloud Practitioner); Google Colab GPU/TPU training
- Other Docker, Git, Linux/Unix, Jenkins, OOP, data structures and algorithms, Kafka, Redis
- Workplace Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Confluence, Wekan

# **Professional Experience**

### **Data Science Software Engineer II – Wood Mackenzie**

September 2022 – Current | Calgary, AB

- Building and automating machine learning pipelines through AWS and Databricks (PySpark)
- Managing 12 software engineers developing web scraping platform for global oil & gas production
- Big Data on Databricks; improving data cleaning process by removing 40% of redundant data
- Reducing infrastructure cost on AWS by 30%; converting monolith to microservices architecture

#### **Machine Learning Engineer –** Salyx Medical

January 2022 – September 2022 | Victoria, BC

- Built a medical-grade machine learning application to predict arterial blood pressure (ABP). Signal processing and feature extraction of patient photoplethysmogram (PPG) recorded signal
- Achieving Systolic MAE of 4.5 mmHg and Diastolic MAE of 3.1 mmHg (same error range as cuff)
- Deployed as a microservice on AWS Lambda for maximum usability and interoperability

## AI/ML Engineering Intern - Convergence Concepts Inc

August 2021 – January 2022 | Vancouver, BC

- Developed an enterprise-level ML application to identify relevant content on webpages, using a multi-channel neural network: metadata, embedding layer and an NLP BERT transformer
- Achieved proficient 90% validation F1 results, trained on over 100,000 examples

- Communicating with clients to translate business requirements and understand data sources
- Deployed high-quality predictive models; used by 10,000+ merchants and publishers

## **Software Engineering Team Lead -** Inventu Research

September 2020 - August 2021 | Victoria, BC

- Led 10 developers amongst embedded electronics, web, and mobile app departments, mentoring in software design and collaborating to help create solutions for a userbase of nearly 1000
- Met 100% of project milestones through leading weekly meetings and organizing technical design
- Designed CI/CD architecture using pipelines and branching strategies for automation of distributed systems
- Applying Test Driven Development and Agile Software Development Life Cycle to optimize workflow by 50%

## **Project Experience**

- **AWS Day Trading System** A distributed system via various AWS EC2 instances, secured in a VPC. Applying software scalability through an application load balancer and auto instance scaling.
- **Duck Hunt AI** Applying transfer learning via ResNet, MobileNet and YOLO for object detection on a custom dataset to shoot animated ducks in varying sceneries. Achieved 0.95 mAP with YOLO model.
- **AI MNIST Pipeline** Developed an articulate ML life cycle with a user interface: data acquisition, EDA, preprocessing, model training, and deployment. Achieved 0.03 categorical cross-entropy loss
- **IMDb Rating Prediction System** Used Neural Networks, Decision Trees and Random Forests to predict movie ratings on a scale from 0 to 10 with a regression MAE value of 0.68. Involved EDA, data processing and modeling of Kaggle datasets
- Machine Learning Models Exploration Implemented Perceptron, ID3 Decision Tree, K-Means Clustering, and Naïve-Bayes algorithms from scratch to evaluate their performance/ metrics and to investigate the reliability with their corresponding ML library functions

#### **Certifications**

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner	2022
Accomplishments	
<ul> <li>Engineers and Geoscientists BC Achievement Award in Software Engineering</li> </ul>	2023
SGI Corporate Scholarship	2019
<ul> <li>Alexander Rutherford Scholarship for Academic Excellence</li> </ul>	2017
University of Victoria Entrance Scholarship for Academic Excellence	2017

#### References

- > Cristian Najera Al Engineer, Convergence Concepts, Vancouver BC
- > Sergio Perez Engineering Lead, Ergonomyx Technologies Canada, Victoria BC
- > Tim Fitzgerald Operations Lead, Stantec, Calgary AB

Databricks Accredited Generative Al Fundementals

2023

<sup>\*</sup>Contact information available upon request

<sup>\*</sup>More detailed project descriptions and code available at https://nolankurylo.github.io/